Selby Kendrick

Full Stack Software Engineer at Keletaire, Inc

selby.kendrick@gmail.com

Summary

I have always had a passion for finding effective and efficient solutions to difficult, practical problems. I am a full-time software engineering student at Louisiana State University (LSU) and work as a full-stack software engineer at Keletaire, Inc, a start-up here in Baton Rouge. I began teaching myself C++ and Arch Linux while in middle school around the age of 12. You can check out an archived version of my first website here: http:// goo.gl/GtSnV9 As a freshman at West Feliciana High School (WFHS) I was a big fan of Digg and Slashdot. Tired of dealing with server crashes of posted links, I wrote the Firefox extension CacheIt! so cached copies were a click away. http://goo.gl/E26yTL I also wrote a simple before-its-time "cloud file-sharing webapp" similar to Dropbox as a freshman so we could transfer files between home and school because the use of flashdrives was forbidden. It was used by a few dozen students to share a few hundred files while I attended WFHS. I left WFHS to attend the Louisiana School for Math, Science, and the Arts (LSMSA) as a junior and finally had the opportunity to take my first few programming classes. I graduated from LSMSA with a college prep diploma in 2010. Now I help create http://sparehanger.com/, a new way to find and share clothes and outfits, and manage the platform it runs so as to be as stable and snappy as possible. I love and am intrigued by algorithms, machine learning, networking, big data analytics, trend prediction, and everything the future holds for us. I am a fitness buff, a bitcoin and namecoin nerd, and have an interest in genetic research. Beyond that, music has always been a huge part of my life. http://www.last.fm/user/n344853835 You can also check out my Open Source Report Card, but it's really just for fun. http://osrc.dfm.io/selbyk May we have the pleasure of working together to build something great. =)

Experience

Full-stack Software Engineer at Keletaire

April 2011 - Present (3 years 10 months)

I help build http://sparehanger.com/ with two other spectacular guys, and we have come a long way. We are trying to be a new way to find & share clothing and outfits. If what we do seems interesting to you, let me know. We may be expanding soon. - Worked with the Yii web framework to develop a web application - Work extensively in HTML, PHP, JavaScript, CSS - Work with Ember.js to design a modern, interactive Javascript front end - Develop cache-driven image storage & retrieval system - Develop cache-driven RESTful api, with authentication system - Use puppet & vagrant to deploy, provision, and mantain Amazon EC2 as well as local development servers - Configure and maintain Amazon EC2 production & staging servers running Debian Linux - Help design & administrate sparehanger's relational storage system (MySQL) - Work with Tomcat & Solr to integrate fast auto-complete & full-text search into sparehanger - Develop sparehanger into its public beta stage

1 recommendation available upon request

Scripter / Web Designer / Computer Technician at Freelance

2004 - Present (11 years)

I have been helping others create websites and diagnose/repair computer problems since I was a middle school student at West Feliciana, my hometown.

Contracted Developer at Everlane

March 2014 - April 2014 (2 months)

Buy a shirt, you'll love it. - Started migrating backend Admin panel from Bootstrap 2 to Bootstrap 3 * I had hoped to spend a summer at Everlane; however, an inury requiring 2 surgeries on my wrist and a few months of physical therapy caused an unexpected leave of absence. You'll notice a 4 month dip in my open source contributions as well. During recovery, Keletaire reached out to me, and I began doing server and dev-ops work, which eventually turned into a full-time job that I can maintain while finishing up school.

Teaching Assistant at Louisiana School for Math, Science, and the Arts

August 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 10 months)

I work as a Teaching Assistant under Sanjeetha Peters. - Graded programming homework & assignments - Helped students struggling with C++ & Java

Skills & Expertise

Open Source

Linux System Administration

MVC Architecture

Database Design

Machine Learning

PHP

C++

Node.js

Python

Amazon EC2

Ember.js

SQL

jQuery

Nginx

MySQL

Solr

Git

Vagrant

Yii

Apache

Bash

Linux

FOSS

Arch Linux

Programming

Heroku

PhoneGap

HTML 5

CSS3

JavaScript

Debian

Ubuntu

Boost C++

FANN

HTML/Javascript/CSS

Web Applications

CSS

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

SaaS

 \mathbf{C}

Education

Louisiana State University

Software Engineering, Computer Science, 2010 - 2015

Activities and Societies: The CSC Guild

Louisiana School for Math, Science, and the Arts

Louisiana State High School Diploma, LSMSA College Prep Diploma, General Studies, 2008 - 2010

Activities and Societies: chorale

Languages

German

Interests

linux, arch linux, fitness, music, bitcoin, namecoin, analytics, big data, artificial neural networks, algorithms

Selby Kendrick

Full Stack Software Engineer at Keletaire, Inc

selby.kendrick@gmail.com



1 person has recommended Selby

"Selby is, by far, the most pleasurable person I've had the experience of working with. Not only does he demonstrate a high level of expertise in the field of software-engineering, but is a team-oriented, self-motivated individual who gives his all in whatever the task may be. Not only this, but he is a quick learner who is constantly learning new and existing technologies and has clear undeniable passion for what he does. He is a clear asset to any company that he is a part of!"

— Adam Dunmars, Software Engineer, Keletaire, Inc., worked directly with Selby at Keletaire

Contact Selby on LinkedIn